Artificial and Ephemera 060
People's Archive, MLK Library
Artificial and Ephemeral Collection
1769
People's Archive, MLK Library
060
27.5 Linear feet
55 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Advertisements Series 2: African-Americans Series 3: Airports Series 4: Apartments Series 5: Art Galleries Series 6: Artists and Art Series 7: Autographs Series 8: Bags and Envelopes Series 9: Banks Series 10: Bicentennial Series 11: Biography Series 12: Bridges Series 13: Buildings Series 14: Business Series 15: Calendars Series 16: Calling/Business Cards Series 17: Canals Series 18: Cartoons Series 19: Cemeteries Series 20: Centennial Series 21: Charity Series 22: Children Series 23: Children and Convalescent Homes Series 24: Churches Series 25: Circles and Squares Series 26: City Planning Series 27: Civil Defense Series 28: Civil War Series 29: Colleges and Universities Series 30: Correspondence Series 31: Crime Series 32: Description of Washington D.C. Series 33: Discrimination Series 34: Embassies Series 35: Ethnic Groups Series 36: Events Series 37: Exhibitions Series 38: Fire Department Series 39: Flags Series 40: Funerals Series 41: Gardening Series 42: Geology Series 43: Halls Series 44: Health Series 45: Hospitals Series 46: Hotels Series 47: Houses Series 48: Housing Series 49: Inaugurations Series 50: Invitations Series 51: Land Records Series 52: Lectures, Speeches and Meetings Series 53: Libraries Series 54: Liquor Series 55: Lottery Series 56: Maps Series 57: Markets Series 58: Military Series 59: Militia Series 60: Monuments and Memorials Series 61: Mosques Series 62: Moving Pictures Series 63: Museums Series 64: Music Series 65: Newsletters Series 66: Newspapers Series 67: Parades Series 68: Parks Series 69: Photography Series 70: Picketing, Protests and Demonstrations Series 71: Playgrounds Series 72: Police Department Series 73: Politics and Government Series 74: Population Series 75: Presidents in Washington Series 76: Prisons and Reformatories Series 77: Prohibition and Temperance Series 78: Real Estate Series 79: Residential Sections Series 80: Restaurants Series 81: Rivers Series 82: Schools Series 83: Societies, Clubs and Organizations Series 84: Sports Series 85: Stickers Series 86: Streets Series 87: Synagogues Series 88: Theatre and Theatres Series 89: Tickets Series 90: Tourism Series 91: Transportation Series 92: Trees Series 93: Water Supply Series 94: Waterfront Series 95: World War I Series 96: World War II Series 97: Zoo
Biographical / Historical
Collection artificially created by D.C. Public Library
Custodial History
The collection was artificially created by the D.C. Public Library and primarily consists of rare and/or historical documents, which were removed from the Washingtoniana Vertical File Collection to ensure their preservation. Small groupings of materials and single items donated to D.C. Public Library which are not placed in the vertical files are added to this collection regularly.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains letters, programs, meeting minutes, speeches, event tickets, brochures, pamphlets, invitations, financial records, legislative materials, political memorabilia, and other rare items dating primarily from the 19th through the mid- 20th century.
Of particular significance are letters, petitions, and legislative acts documenting the work of elected and appointed mayors; a Board of Alderman; and City Councils from 1802 through the early 1870s in the "Politics and Government Series." The District had an appointed Mayor and elected City Council from 1802 through 1812; in 1812 a Charter amendment allowed for the election of all city officials.
Another important series includes the newsletters, correspondence, flyers, programs, and yearbooks of the numerous civic, social, and cultural organizations starting in the late 19th century. These materials are primarily in two series: "Civic and Citizens Associations," and "Societies, Clubs and Organizations." Other notable items include Congressional speeches on the abolition of slavery from 1833 through the 1860s; guidebooks and published descriptions of Washington, D.C.; musical scores celebrating Washington, D.C. history and events; architectural specifications for the U.S. Capitol, House Office Building, Post Office and other local buildings; local business advertising; documentation for the founding and development of the Washington City Canal; Centennial memorabilia and programs; letters and autographs of famous persons and families; and publications and programs about or from churches, colleges, and schools in the District.
Ephemera; Neighborhoods; Associations, institutions, etc; African Americans; Art and Artifacts; Performing Arts; Architecture; Business; Centennial celebrations, etc; Philanthropy; Land Use; Education; Politics and government; Municipal services; Tourism; Religion; Sports; Civil rights; Wars; Leisure; Plants; Animals; Black people
- Advertisements - 1857 - 1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  "A Guide to House-Keepers and Others. A List of Everything Wanted for Furnishing a House"
- Advertisements - 1879 - 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Advertisements - 1883 - 1883 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Advertisements - 1884 - 1884 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Advertisements - 1885 - 1885 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Advertisements - 1889 - 1889 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Advertisements - 1890 - 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Advertisements - 1910 - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Advertisements - 1913 - 1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Advertisements - 1914 - 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Advertisements - 1920 - 1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Advertisements - 1932 - 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Advertisements - 1926 - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Advertisements - 1930 - 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Advertisements - 1931 - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Advertisements - 1932 - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Advertisements - 1939 - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Advertisements - 1940 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Advertisements - 1954 - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Advertisements - Undated - Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- African-Americans - Court Cases - District of Columbia V Thompson Restaurant, ca. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- African-Americans - Defense Training and Jobs for Negros - Defense Training and Jobs for Negros, 1942-02-07 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- African-Americans - Exhibits - Douglasses of Washington (Box 1, Folder 23)
- African-Americans - Hearings - House Committee on the District of Columbia, 1916-02-11 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  "Intermarriage of Whites and Negroes in the District of Columbia and Separate Accommodations in Street Cars for Whites and Negroes in the District of Columbia"
- African-Americans - Improving Economic and Cultural Status of the Negro in the District of Columbia - Improving Economic and Cultural Status of the Negro in the District of Columbia, 1954-07 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- African-Americans - Improving Economic and Cultural Status of the Negro in the District of Columbia - Improving Economic and Cultural Status of the Negro in the District of Columbia, 1954-09 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- African-Americans - Message from Abraham Lincoln - Message from Abraham Lincoln, 1863-12-17 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  communicating a letter addressed to him from a committee of gentlemen representing the Freedmen's Aid Societies of Boston, New York, Philadelphia, and Cincinnati, in relation to the freedmen under the proclamation of emancipation
- African-Americans - In the Shadow of the Capitol - In the Shadow of the Capitol, 1981-04-12 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  A Colloquium, An Experiment in Collective Memory, The Folger Shakespeare Library
- African-Americans - Publications - "No Negro Need Apply" by Harlan E. Glazier, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  damaged
- African-Americans - Publications - "Tape Recordings of Oral History Interviews in the Estate of Letitia Woods Brown" by Kathryn C. Ray, 1980-05 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- African-Americans - Speech by E. H. Rollins - Speech by E. H. Rollins, 1862-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  on the bill for the release of certain persons held to service or labor in the District of Columbia
- African-Americans - Speech by H. G. Blake - Speech by H. G. Blake, 1862-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- African-Americans - Speech of J. A. Wright - Speech of J. A. Wright, 1862-04-01 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Slavery in the District of Columbia
- African-Americans - Speech by J. M. Ashley - Speech by J. M. Ashley, 1862-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- African-Americans - Speech by James A. Bayard - Speech by James A. Bayard, 1862-04-08 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Abolition and the Relation of Races
- African-Americans - Speech by John A. Bingham - Speech by John A. Bingham, 1862-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  on the bill to emancipate slaves and prohibit slavery and perpetuate liberty forever in the national capital
- African-Americans - Speech by John Sherman - Speech by John Sherman, 1862-04-02 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Slaves and Slavery: How Affected by the War
- African-Americans - Speech by John P. Hale - Speech by John P. Hale, 1862-03-18 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Abolition of Slavery in the District of Columbia
- African-Americans - Speech by Samuel A. Peugh - Speech by Samuel A. Peugh, 1866-02-05 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  on the Oppressiveness of the Act of Congress of June 25, 1864, and the Utter Inability of the Citizens of Washington to Meet Its Requirements
- African-Americans - Speech by W. P. Fessenden - Speech by W. P. Fessenden, 1862-04-01 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- African-Americans - Speech by W. T. Willey - Speech by W. T. Willey, 1862-03-20 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- African-Americans - Report - Freedman's Relief Association, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- African-Americans - Report - Select Committee on Slavery in the District of Columbia, 1836-05-18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- African-Americans - Resolutions - Legislature of Kentucky, 1836-03-16 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Against any interference on the part of the General Government, societies, or individuals, on the subject of slavery in the District of Columbia
- Airports - George Washington Air Junction - George Washington Air Junction, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Airports - Washington Hoover Airport - Washington Hoover Airport, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Apartments - Apartment Shoppers Guide - Apartment Shoppers Guide, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Apartments - Chastleton, The - Chastleton, The (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Apartments - Chatsworth - Chatsworth, ca. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Art Galleries - Children's Federal Art Gallery - Children's Federal Art Gallery, 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Society of Washington Artists
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Specifications, ca. 1858 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Art Galleries - Corcoran Gallery of Art - Catalogue, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Art Galleries - National Building Museum - National Building Museum (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Catalogue, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Catalogue, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Art Galleries - National Gallery of Art - Exhibitions, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Art Galleries - National Museum of African Art - National Museum of African Art, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Art Galleries - National Museum of American Art - National Museum of American Art, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Art Galleries - National Portrait Gallery - National Portrait Gallery, 1962-1989 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Art Galleries - National Portrait Gallery - Exhibitions, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Brochures (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Bulletin of the Phillips Collection, 1928-02 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Exhibitions, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Extracts from the Minutes of the First Annual Meeting of Trustees of the Phillips Memorial Art Gallery, 1920-07-23 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - List of Original Kodachrome 2x2" Slides (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - List of Reproductions and Publications (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Art Galleries - Phillips Memorial Gallery - Phillips Collection and Related Thoughts on Art, The by Duncan Phillips (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery, 1940-1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Articles, 1944-1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Catalogue (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Art Galleries - Whyte Bookshop and Gallery - Exhibitions (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Artists and Art - Age of Spirituality - Age of Spirituality, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Exhibition at the Metropolitan Museum of Art
- Artists and Art - American Art Annual - American Art Annual, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Artists and Art - Art in Our Country - Art in Our Country, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Artists and Art - General Information and List of Paintings and Sculpture, National Gallery of Art - General Information and List of Paintings and Sculpture, National Gallery of Art, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Artists and Art - La Nouvelle Boheme by Flora Orr - La Nouvelle Boheme by Flora Orr, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Artists and Art - Works of Art in Washington by Leila Mechlin - Works of Art in Washington by Leila Mechlin, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Artists and Art - Artists Cooperative - Artists Cooperative (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Artists and Art - Washington Project for the Arts - Another Washington by Joel E. Siegel, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Autographs - Autographs - Autographs (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Bags and Envelopes - Bags and Envelopes - Bags and Envelopes (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Banks - Bank Notes - Bank Notes, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  The Bank of Metropolis 5 Dollar note
- Banks - Bank of the United States - Report to the Stockholders, 1825-07-26 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  binding damaged
- Banks - Checks - Checks, 1878-1930 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Banks include: Riggs, second national bank and others. most checks are blank
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Freedman's Bank, 1909 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  Freedman's Savings and Trust Company
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Annual Reports, 1876-1898 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Annual Reports, 1899-1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - "The Washers and Scrubbers: The Men Who Robbed Them" by F. C. Adams, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Reports, 1898-1910 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  "Dividends of Freedman's Savings and Trust Company" (1898 July 1) - Report (1910 March 22) - "Reimbursement of Depositors of Freedman's Savings and Trust Company" (1910 May 6) - "To Reimburse Depositors of Late Freedman's Savings and Trust Company" (1910 July 2)
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Resolutions, 1888-08-15 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  US Senate
- Banks - Freedman's Bank - Statements to Congress, 1912-06-04 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  by Rev. James L White
- Banks - Letterhead - Letterhead, 1911-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  cut from various correspondence
- Banks - Riggs Bank - "The Association of the Oldest Inhabitants of the District of Columbia Honors Riggs Bank" upon receipt of the 2001 Business Legends Award (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Banks - Treasury Department - Savings Bonds, ca. 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Banks - Second National Bank - Second National Bank, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Banks - Washington Loan and Trust Company - Washington Loan and Trust Company, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Bicentennial - District of Columbia - Bicentennial of Territory of Columbia and City of Washington, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  2 first day issue District of Columbia stamps; exhibitor badge with rope; bag and other items
- Bicentennial - George Washington's Birth - Bicentennial of George Washington's Birth, 1932-02-22 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Ball Program
- Biography - Anderson, Marian - Anderson, Marian (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Research compiled by Patrick Hayes
- Biography - Anthony, Susan B. - Anthony, Susan B., 1900-02-15 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Program fro 80th Birthday celebration
- Biography - Bell, Alexander Melville - Bell, Alexander Melville (Box 4, Folder 15)
  by John Hitz (damaged)
- Biography - Brown, Wesley - Brown, Wesley, 1954-11-18 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Letter to Mrs. Thelma L. Baltimore. Mostly biographical topics include Naval Career, US Naval Academy, Howard University, and Dunbar High School.
- Biography - Chubb, Isaac - Chubb, Isaac, 1956-06-03 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Last Will and Testament
- Biography - Dahlgren, Madeleine Vinton Goddard - Dahlgren, Madeleine Vinton Goddard, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  4 part article in "Barquilla de la Santa Maria" Bulletin of the Catholic Record Society
- Biography - Douglass, Frederick - Douglass, Frederick, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  "Frederick Douglass: The Clarion Voice" by John W. Blassingame (2 copies); National Frederick Douglass Center
- Biography - Gillison, Joan Mayes - Gillison, Joan Mayes, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  ANC 1A05
- Biography - Grant, Ulysses S. - "Recollections of General Grant" by George W. Childs, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Biography - Hayes, Rutherford B. - Hayes, Rutherford B., 1948-05 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Information on the Hayes Memorial Library published by the American Association for State and Local History May 1948
- Biography - Headley, Albert J. - Headley, Albert J., 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  policeman
- Biography - Hoover, Herbert Clark - Hoover, Herbert Clark, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Campaign Material entitled "Don't Gamble with the Destiny of Your Nation" issued by the Republican National Committee
- Biography - Horydczak, Theodor - " Discovering Theodor Horydczak's Washington" by Beverly W. Brannan, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Biography - Jackson. Shirley Ann - "Science Matters: A Conversation with Shirley Ann Jackson, Theoretical Physicist and President of Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, the Nation's Oldest Technical University.," by Curtis Stephen, 2006-05 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Biography - James, Charles - James, Charles, 1908-01-20 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Biography - LaFayette - LaFayette, 1824-1916 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Clippings
- Biography - Landon, Alfred M. - "Landon: What he Stands For," Editor David Hinshaw, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Biography - Lincoln, Abraham - Lincoln, Abraham, 1954-1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Lincoln Sesquicentennial
- Biography - Marshall, Peter - Marshall, Peter, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  "Prayers Offered by the Chaplain the Rev. Peter Marshall, D.D. at the Opening of the Daily Sessions of the Senate of the United States During the Eightieth Congress, 1947-1948"
- Biography - Manning, Marie - Manning, Marie (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Biography - Miner, Myrtilla - Miner, Myrtilla, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Biography - Nalle, John C. - Nalle, John C., 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Biography - Roosevelt, Eleanor - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1959-10-15 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Biography - Smith, Chloethiel Woodard - "A Female Modernist in the Classical Capital: Chloethiel Woodard Smith and The Architecture of Southwest Washington, DC" by Catherine W. Zipf (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Biography - Sousa, John Philip - Sousa, John Philip, 1897-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Concert Programs
- Biography - Stone, Elizabeth - "Mrs. Elizabeth J. Stone; Sketch" by Helen Waldo Burnside, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Biography - Thompson, Charles H. - Thompson, Charles H., 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Biography - Truax, Robert A. - Truax, Robert A., 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Biography - Washington, Booker T. - "Booker T. Washington: An Appreciation of the Man and his Times" by Barry Mackintosh, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Biography - Washington, George - Birthday Celebrations, 1881-1928 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Biography - Washington, George - "Chronological the George Washington Gavel" by R. Baker Harris, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Biography - Washington, George - "The First President's Interest in Washington as Told by Himself" by John Ball Osborne, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Biography - Washington, George - "George Washington's Gifts to Education" by L. Lowell Johnson, 1933-06 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Biography - Washington, George - "Last Will and Testament of George Washington of Mount Vernon", 1911 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Biography - Washington, George - "Washington and His Planning Activities" by John Nolen, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Biography - Washington, George - "Washington's Bequest to a National University", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Biography - Washington, George - "Washington's Washington: Know the Little City He Knew" by Frank and Cortelle Hutchins, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Biography - Wesley, Charles Harris - Wesley, Charles Harris, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Biography - Wesley, Dorothy Porter - Wesley, Dorothy Porter, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Bridges - Cabin John Bridge - Cabin John Bridge, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Bridges - Tafe Bridge - Tafe Bridge, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Duke Ellington Bridge
- Bridges - Washington Bridge - Washington Bridge, 1832-03-31 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Buildings - Acts - "The Shipstead-Luce Act: Rules and Regulations Administered by the National Commission of Fine Arts", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Buildings - Architects - Cluss, Adolf, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Buildings - Central Library (Carnegie Library Building) - Central Library (Carnegie Library Building), 1953 (Box 5, Folder 26)